Byron Hulcher

byronhulcher@gmail.com github.com/byronhulcher

(301) 356 - 3751 Brooklyn, NY

SUMMARY

Programmer and public speaker with hands-on experience in full-stack web development, product design, and game development. Collaborative team-player who likes to use communication expertise and planning skills to build user-facing products from whiteboard to deployment

SKILLS

Client-side Javascript: React, Ember, Backbone

Additional interests: offline-first, ServiceWorkers

Server-side Javascript: Node.js, Express, Hapi, Grunt/Gulp, npm

Additional interests: Nodebots, text generation, Electron

CSS: Bootstrap, SASS, LESS, Flexbox

Additional interests: PostCSS, animation

Also: Java, Python + Django, git, MySQL, MongoDB, CouchDB, Unity

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer @ Meetup NY, NY (Oct 2014 - Present)

- Created customer facing pages and flows for new enterprise product
- Moved Meetup.com front-end towards a mobile-first responsive design using in-house CSS framework
- Supported other front-end engineers with back-end code in Python and Java

Full-Stack Software Engineer @ JW Player NY, NY (Nov 2013 - Sep 2014)

 Maintained and implemented new features for the existing JW Player Angular.js dashboard and Python-driven back-end platform

Full-Stack Developer @ Stray Boots NY, NY (Dec 2012 - Nov 2013)

 Designed and implemented API and dashboard for user accounts and multi-device gameplay, including updates to Backbone.js driven front-end

Full-Stack Developer @ Offerpop NY, NY (Jun 2011 - Dec 2012)

 Built Facebook apps using Django and Backbone.js for clients such as MTV, Marvel, Universal Music, Disney, Unilever, and Wells Fargo

EDUCATION

B.S. Computer Science, B.S. Games & Simulations Arts and Sciences Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute (Sep 2007- May 2011)